dimensionsdance.ie 2014-12-15

# Privacy Notice : Dimensions Dance, Dance Dimensions Dublin, Irelands leading stockist of Ballet, Irish dancing. gymnastics and dance accessories.

**Your privacy is very important to Dimensions Dance.**

This Privacy Policy describes the principles and practices that apply to Personal Information (defined below) collected from users of our services ("you") on our Website:

**In summary**

* We will not collect Personal Information without your knowledge and permission;
* We will not knowingly disclose your Personal Information to third parties, except  
   as provided in this Privacy Policy;
* We will allow you to view, correct or remove your Personal Information; and
* We will take reasonable steps to protect the security of the Personal Information  
   we collect from you.
  
The remainder of this policy describes our Personal Information handling practices in detail.

## 1\. Definitions

In this Privacy Policy, terms that commence with a capital letter are defined in this section or in the preamble

" **Guest** " means an individual who can search and purchase Products or Services on the Website without being a Member.

" **Member** " means an individual who has registered with the Website.

" **Member ID** " means the email address you use (with your password) to login to our Website

" **Dimensions Dance** " or " **we** " means Dimensions Dance.ie and / or Dimensions Dance Wear Limited, the company name under which the Dimensions Dance trading name is registered.

" **Personal Information** " means any information, recorded in any form, about an identified individual, or an individual whose identity may be inferred from the information. This includes, for example, name, email and mailing address and telephone number, billing and account information, and other information incidental to providing Products or Services (including information about individuals travelling with you)

" **Products or Services** " means the clothing and dance wear products available from the Website.

To " **Purchase** " means to book, reserve or purchase

" **Session Data** " means usage information, such as the type of Internet browser and operating system an individual uses, the domain name of the site from which the individual came, the date, time and duration of the visit, number of visits, average time spent on the individual's site, pages viewed, domain name of the individual, and number of cookies accumulated

" **Website** " means the www.Dimensionsdance.ie site together with the respective content, Products and Services available from that site.

" **Subscriber** " means an individual who elects to receive offers or promotions from Dimensions Dance without becoming a Member or a Guest.

## 2.Consent

BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING OUR WEBSITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW.

If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any Personal Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personal Information, we may not be able to provide you with Products or Services that can be offered on our Website only if we have access to certain Personal Information.

**Minors**  
Minors (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register for, use, or Purchase the Products or Services available on our Website. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor.

## 3\. What Personal Information we collect

We collect only such information as necessary to provide Products and Services to you.

**When you are just visiting.**  
You can visit certain areas of our Website without revealing who you are or signing-in. When you visit our Website as a Visitor, Guest, or Member, we collect Session Data through cookies and pixel tags.

**When you register as a Member.**  
If you register with us as a Member, we collect Personal Information that is necessary to provide the Products and Services offered on our Website. We require that you provide your name and email address. You also need to choose a password, which will be required to gain access to portions of our Website reserved for Member use. We might also request your home postcode.

**When you Purchase Products or Services as a Member.**  
When you Purchase Products or Services from our Website as a Member, you must provide payment or other necessary information.

**When you use the Website as a "Guest".**  
If you are not a Member, you may elect to use our Website as a Guest. If you Purchase Products or Services as a Guest, you must provide Personal Information to complete the booking.

**When you "Subscribe".**  
When you become a Subscriber, we collect your name and email address, so that you may receive offers or promotions from Dimensions Dance without becoming a Member or Guest.

**When we advertise on third party sites.**  
When you visit a site on which we advertise, and click through our advertisement, we may place cookies on your computer, or use pixel tags. The information that we collect through this technology is not personally identifiable.

**When we send emails or e-newsletters.**  
When we send emails, e-newsletters, or when you forward a promotion or search results to a third party, we may insert a pixel in the email.

## 4\. How we use the information we collect

We use Personal Information in order to provide and enhance the Products or Services offered on our Website:

To record your product preferences

To issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments;

To provide tips or guidance on how to use our Website, inform you of new features on our Website, or provide other information that may be of interest to users;

To personalize the service we provide to you, tailor your experience at our Website to your interests and make appropriate recommendations;

To send you emails, e-newsletters, personalized offers via direct messaging or other communications about our services, if you have subscribed to receive this information or you have not advised us that you do not wish to receive such communications; To manage our Website, diagnose technical problems, improve content, and allocate the resources of our systems so that your experience with our Website is as efficient as possible;

To process and track your transactions and to send you information about our company and business partners' products and services and other information and materials that may be of interest to you but only if you have granted us permission to do so or we are otherwise able to do so under applicable law;

To develop, enhance, market, sell or provide Dimensions Dance' Products or Services, or those of companies with which we have a commercial relationship, but only if you have granted us permission to do so or we are otherwise able to do so under applicable law;

To evaluate credit standing and to match credit bureau or credit reporting agency information; to investigate, detect and protect Dimensions Dance and other third parties against error, negligence, breach of contract, fraud, theft and other illegal activities;

To effect a corporate transaction, in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off, or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in regular course of business;

To audit compliance with our policies and contractual obligations;

As permitted by, and to comply with, any legal or regulatory requirements or provisions; or

For any other purpose to which you consent.

**Session Data**  
We use Session Data, collected through cookies and pixel tags, to better understand how our Website is navigated, how many visitors arrive at specific pages, the length and frequency of stays at our Website, the variety of searches of our Website's database, the types of browsers and computer operating systems used by our visitors and the Internet Protocol addresses from which visitors connect to our Website. We also use this information to improve our Website content and ease of use, to personalize and improve your individual viewing experiences on our Website, and provide information that may be of interest to you.

**Pixel Tags**  
We use pixel tags to monitor the open rate of our communications. This helps us understand the effectiveness of communications we send. We do not use this information for any other purpose.

**Aggregated Information**  
Aggregated information is information, recorded in any form, about more than one individual, where the identity of the individual is not known, and cannot be inferred from the information. We may use aggregated information to describe our user base to current or potential partners, investors and advertisers; after a survey, to understand and respond to market needs and preferences; or to make recommendations to other users of our Website.

**What we do NOT do**  
We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, Member ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited email or telephone communication.

## 5\. To whom we disclose Personal Information

From time to time, we may disclose your Personal Information as follows:

To organizations that perform services for or on behalf of Dimensions Dance, for example to provide customer service, deliver products, ship items, process credit cards, for research, marketing, data processing, to measure the use of our Website or to facilitate usage by a Visitor. We will share with these companies only that Personal Information which they need to work on our behalf. Some of these service providers may be located in countries outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). Your Personal Information will be provided to these organizations only if they agree to use such information solely for the purpose of providing services to Dimensions Dance, and under the instructions of Dimensions Dance, and with respect to that information, to act in a manner consistent with the relevant principles articulated in this Policy. **By submitting your Personal Information, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your data outside the EEA.**

We may collaborate with other companies to offer you additional Products or Services. We will share Personal Information that is necessary for these other companies to provide the Products or Services that you have requested.

This policy will not cover the use of your Personal Information by these other companies. We encourage you to read a company's privacy policy before requesting any of its products or services.

**Please note that there are circumstances where the use or disclosure of Personal Information may be justified or permitted, or where Dimensions Dance may be obligated to disclose information without consent. Such circumstances may include:**

To protect our Website and our rights under our website terms and conditions of use; to protect ourselves against liability or prevent fraudulent activity; or where it is necessary to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain.

To effect a corporate transaction, in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off, or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in regular course of business.

**Where the information is public.**  
To our insurers and to regulatory agencies.

If required to comply with an order or warrant issued or an order made by a court, person or body with jurisdiction to compel the production of information, or to comply with the rules or court relating to the production of records.

If we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.

To a person who needs the information because of an emergency that threatens the life, health, or security of an identifiable person or group.

Where it is necessary to collect monies owing to us.

## 6\. How we retain and store Personal information

We will retain your Personal Information in our databases in accordance with our document management, retention and destruction policy and applicable laws. This period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with us, but it will be only as long as it is necessary for us to have sufficient information to respond to any issues that may arise later. For example, we may need or be required to retain information to allow you to obtain credit for the trip you Purchased but had to cancel. We may also need the retain certain information to prevent fraudulent activity; to protect ourselves against liability, permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain; or if we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.

Your Personal Information will be stored in secured locations, and on servers controlled by Dimensions Dance, located either at our offices, or at the offices of our service providers, as described below.

## 7\. How we protect Personal Information

Dimensions Dance employs physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help protect the confidentiality and integrity of Personal Information and to reduce the risk of loss, misuse, unauthorized access disclosure or modification of Personal Information. When Personal Information is sent to our service providers, we require, in our contracts with them, that they protect all Personal Information in a manner consistent with the principles articulated in this Privacy Policy.

If you choose to contact Dimensions Dance through the Website, you should be aware that any information transmitted electronically via the World Wide Web might not be secure. Dimensions Dance assumes no liability for the loss of any information that you transmit to us via the World Wide Web. However, should you choose to pay by credit card when making a booking, reservation or purchase on the Website, your card details are encrypted for the transaction.

In communicating with you, we may send email as unencrypted plain text because we are aware that most Members, Guests, or Subscribers cannot readily process encrypted email. This is done for your convenience, but with the security concern that, if misrouted or intercepted, it could be read more easily than encrypted email.

## 8\. Privacy

**Cookies and pixel tags**  
A Cookie is a small text file that our computer sends to your computer, and that your computer sends back to us each time you make a request from our Website. A cookie contains a unique identification number that identifies the visitor's browser, but not necessarily the visitor. A pixel tag is a small graphic image similar to a cookie.

When you access our Website, our computer may seek to place "cookies" or "pixel tags" on your personal computer to collect Session Data. Cookies and pixel tags help us recognize you when you visit our Website again. Unless a visitor specifically informs us of his/her identity (e.g. by registering with us), we will not know who the individual visitor is.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit. You can learn more about the use of cookies by visiting [http://networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/) or <http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie.>

If you decide not to accept our cookies, you will be able to access those parts of our Website that are available to the general public, but you will not be able to access many of the Products and Services offered at our Website.

In addition, in our emails and other communications, we will include instructions on how to unsubscribe and inform us of preferences if you decide you do not want to receive any future marketing or promotional emails from us.

**Monitoring**  
Dimensions Dance may from time to time monitor and review any information transmitted or received through the Website for quality assurance and other purposes. We reserve the right to censor, edit, remove, or prohibit the transmission or receipt of any information that Dimensions Dance deems inappropriate, or in violation of these Terms and Conditions. During monitoring, the information may be examined, recorded, or copied.

## 9\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

We may change or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. We may also undergo a change of ownership. We will post an appropriate notice of changes to the Privacy Policy and changes or ownership on our Website. Privacy Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date we post the revised Privacy Policy to the Website, as well as to existing information held by us.

## 10\. Contact Information

Dimensions Dance.  
124 Drumcondra Road,  
Upper Drumcondra,  
Dublin 9,  
Ireland. 

For more information you can call us on +353 1 836 0125  
or alternatively you can email us on [info@dimensionsdance.ie](mailto:info@dimensionsdance.ie)
